Gerald R. Gill Papers MS170
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Writings, 1980 -- 2007; MS170.009; 2.9 Linear Feet 2 record cartons and 1 document box
  - "There is No Room in Boston for Jim Crowism": Black Protest in Boston, 1935-1945 drafts, 1998; MS170.009.047.00012; 3 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 12-14)
  - "There was a Time…" An Alumnus Reflects on Black Student Life at Lafayette College, 1966-1970, drafts, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.009.047.00013; 2 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 15-16)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary of the African-American Cultural Center at Tufts, 1999; MS170.009.047.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Twentieth Anniversary of the African-American Center at Tufts, 1989; MS170.009.047.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Writing on "Academia and Activism: the 1960s and the 1990s" panel discussion, circa 1990s; MS170.009.047.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Writing on Historical Biographies, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.009.047.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Youth Unemployment: A Documentary Proposal, circa 1988; MS170.009.047.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 47, Folder 21)
- Digital files, 1992 -- 2007; MS170.010; 309.22 Megabytes; 1,016 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains files that were saved on Gill's office computer at Tufts University, and 3.5 inch floppy disks and CDs stored with his computer. The majority of the files on the computer were found in a temp folder, while the others were saved in a documents folder or were unarranged on the desktop. Most of the files are student work produced by students in a number of his courses. Other materials include syllabi for courses not taught by Gill, symposium and conference programs and fliers, documents relating to university business and administration, writings by colleagues, teaching materials, and advertisements for campus events.
  All student work, two files found on the computer, and the content of one CD are subject to privacy concerns and copyright restrictions and can be accessed in the DCA Reading Room.
  Gill's Tufts email was also discovered on his computer and is described in the Correspondence series.
  - Born-digital records, 1992 -- 2007; MS170.010.00001; 342 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes
    342 files in four directories that maintain Gill's original organization. The files in the "loose" directory were found on his desktop. The files that were found on disks are arranged in directories that have the original disk names.
    - University records, 2003 -- 2007; MS170.010.00001.00001; 23 Digital Object(s); 1.54 Megabytes
      Records relating to official university business are closed for 20 years.
    - Student records and tenure review documents, 2003 -- 2007; MS170.010.00001.00002; 17 Digital Object(s); .488 Megabytes
      Records containing sensitive information regarding students and tenure reviews are restricted for 75 years.
  - Student work and copyrighted born-digital records, 2000 -- 2006; MS170.010.00002; 634 Digital Object(s); 19.6 Megabytes
    Files may only be accessed in the Reading Room - please contact DCA for on-site access.
    114 files of student-produced work, such as papers and take-home exams, are restricted to reading room access out of privacy concerns for the creators.
    Two files are subject to copyright restrictions. One is a published article about white privilege and the other is a news clip of Gerald Gill talking about Coretta Scott King. The contents from the CD On the Way Out contains files for Alexis Esquivel's website and may contain copyrighted material.